# Don't ask me
“不要我”
# What you know is true
“你所知的就是真相”
# Don't have to tell you
“不需要告V你”
# I love your precious heart
“我勰愕囊黄\心”
# I
“我…”
# I was standing
“我站著”
# You were there
“你在那e”
# Two worlds collided
“世界碰撞”
# And they could never tear us apart
“o法⑽分_”
# We could live
“我可以生活…”
# For a thousand years
“登年”
# But if I hurt you
“但若我了你”
# I'd make wine from your tears
“我用你的I酒”
# I told you
“我告V你”
# That we could fly
“我可以w翔”
# 'Cause we all have wings
“因槲都有翅膀”
# But some of us don't know why
“但有些人不知道由”
# I
“我…”
# I was standing
“我站著”
# You were there
“你在那e”
# Two worlds collided
“世界碰撞”
# And they could never
“再也o法…”
# Ever tear us apart #
“⑽分_”
I'm voting for Dukakis.
我投杜卡基斯一票
Hm...
嗯
Well...
那N
Maybe when you have children who need braces
也S你有号需要箍牙
and half of your husband's pay cheque goes to the government, you'll regret that.
但你]X，因檎煞蛞话 收入要o政府r，你後悔
My husband's pay cheque?
我丈夫的收入？
I'm not squeezing one out till I'm 30.
反正我在三十q前不生孩子
Will you still be at the Yarn Barn? That's a great place to raise children.
你不上}吧工作？ f那e最m合B孩子噢
- That's really funny. - I think a year of partying's enough.
-真好笑 -玩一年好了
- She's going to Harvard next fall. - I haven't gotten in yet.
- 伊莉下W期到哈佛升W - ，我未考M去呢
You think Dukakis will provide for America till you squeeze one out?
你真J槎趴基斯能治？
- When can I squeeze one out? - Eighth grade.
- 我何r能生孩子？ - 第八班之後
Excuse me.
Σ黄
Donnie, you're such a dick.
尼，你真是^分
Whoa, Elizabeth! A little hostile there.
W，伊莉!有c骋饽
Maybe Y0U should be in therapy,
是你看心理t生才
then Mom and Dad can pay someone to listen to Y0UR thoughts so we don't have to.
爸便付e人每小r200元 去你l牢}，不再┪!
0K. Tell us why you stopped taking your medication.
那你告V爸 你楹尾辉俜？
- You're such a fuck-ass! - (ELIZABETH LAUGHS)
你真是v精!
- Please. - Did you just call me a fuck-ass?
- 收口 - 你叫我v精？
- (M0M) That's enough. - Go suck a fuck!
- 伊莉，蛄 - 你去啜啜职
- How does one suck a fuck? - Shall I tell you?
- 伊莉你f，什N是啜啜郑 - 你想我告V你？
- Please. - Not at the dinner table.
- f吧 - 我不容忍在桌上有@Nf
- Stop. - Fuck...
- 收 - 的…
- What's a fuck-ass? - (LAUGHS)
什N是v精？
I took a year off to be with you.
我一年]只罹褪榱撕湍阋黄
- What? - How did you know?
- 什N？ - 你怎N知道？
- I didn't know it was a big deal. - It is a big deal.
- ]什N大不了 - @太重要了
I'm reading. Get out.
我在看，出去
Where do you go at night?
你晚上去了哪e？
- Just get out. - Did you toilet-paper the Johnsons' house?
- 你可不可以出去？ - 你用住f臣g屋？
- Is that why you're here? - No.
- 你就是檫@事入恚 - 不
- I stopped rolling houses in the sixth grade. - Where's my son? I don't recognise you.
- 我自第六班後便]用屋了 - l生了何事？我完全不J得@人
Then you take the goddamn pills.
那你楹嗡的不吃？
Bitch.
八婆!
0ur son just called me a bitch.
我的鹤才叫我八婆
You're not a bitch.
你不是八婆
You're bitchin', but you're not a bitch.
你是l牢}，但不是八婆
I want to be a president who makes sure
我想做一保C家不再跟…
that we never again do business with a drug-running Panamanian dictator
毒的裁者…
or funnel aid to the Contras through drug dealers.
做生意的美y
Values begin at the top.
那我便再不
Dukakis... Son of a bitch.
杜卡基斯…狗娘B的
Those are the values I want to bring to the presidency and to the White House.
@是我目y和政府取得的好
- Panama is a friendly country. - Tell him, George.
- 巴拿R是友好的家 - f吧佐治!
I talked to the president of Panama about their money laundering.
我跟巴拿Ry^ 叫他e再洗黑X
Mr Noriega was there, but there was no evidence.
那rK]有C
When the evidence was there, we indicted him.
若有我就起V
(ECHOING GHOSTLY VOICE) Wake up.
醒
I've been watching you.
我一直在看你
Come closer.
^硪稽c
Closer.
再近一c
28 days...
28日
six hours...
6小r
42 minutes...
42分
12 seconds.
12秒
That is when the world will end.
那r便是世界末日
Why?
槭颤N？
Son? Donnie Darko?
路？丁尼？
Donnie Darko? What the heck's going on here?
丁尼!@el生了什N事？
- Who is it? - It's Eddie Darko's kid.
- 那是l？ - 丁艾迪的鹤
He's just a neighbourhood kid.
很抱歉，那只是街坊的孩子
Guess he was sleep-golfing?
那他粲r打高夫幔
Watch out for that drool spot!
看那口水n吧
So let's stay off the links at night, 0K?
夜晚不要再砗幔
(D0NNIE) I'm sorry, Dr Fisher. It... It won't happen again.
Σ黄穑Mt生，不再l生
- (FISHER SIGHS) Kids... - Let's golf.
- 我最憎路 - 打球吧
- No one's allowed. - This is my house.
- 不准M入 - 那是我家
- I said... - This is my house!
- 我f - 那是我家!
Wait a minute.
等一下
- Here's your brother. - It fell in your room.
- 你哥在那e - 你房塌下了
Ms Darko? I'm Bob Garland. I'm with the FAA.
丁太，我叫郭N，家航空局
- The what? - I'm with the FAA. May we speak privately?
- 什N？ - 我是家航空局的，我想为跟你一下
- In private? - Please.
- 为？ -
- And here... - 0K.
- @e… - 好
All right, we have arranged a hotel. Get some sleep and we'll take care of this.
- 我安排了你入住酒店 - 好  xx
- Great. - Thank you.
- 好 - xx
Kids, come on. We're going to a hotel.
孩子戆桑我到酒店
They don't know where it came from.
他不知道怎影l生的
- (TV) Where's Pop? - He's still at work.
- POP呢？ - 他在只
If it fell from the plane... what happened to the plane?
如果他娘wCe掉下去 wC怎N樱
They don't know, Samantha.
丁莎，他不清楚
Can't we make money from this? Can't we sue the airline?
我可否闹兄\利？ 我去告航空公司吧
Shut up, Sam.
]嘴，山姆
Why do I have to sleep with Donnie? He stinks.
槭颤N我要和尼一起睡？ 他臭死了
When you fall asleep tonight,
你今晚睡著的r候
- I'm gonna fart in your face. - I'm telling Mom!
- 我要向著你放屁 - 我要告V
Samantha, don't go over there.
丁莎，不要去那e
Frankie Feedler.
斐法m
You remember. From high school.
你得幔中W同W
Hm... Mm-hm.
嗯
He died. Remember?
他死了.不得？
0n his way to the prom.
在他去I舞的途中
They said he was doomed.
他f他]定要死
Jesus.
天啊!
They could be saying the same thing about Donnie.
他也如此f尼
0ur Donnie.
我的尼
- But he dodged it. - Hm...
尼死e逃生!
He dodged his photograph.
他]去照相
Hm...
嗯
Somebody was watching over him.
有人在O他
(M0M) Mrs Farmer will bring you home after practice. Bye, honey.
法小姐在做完後 你回家，再，H鄣
Donnie... good luck.
尼..祝你好\
- 0h, my God! Tell me everything. - I'm not allowed to talk about it.
- 天啊!快告V我 - 我不能v
- 0h, my God! - Hi, Cherita.
- 哦，上帝! - 嗨，雪 - 收!
You're a celebrity! I called you a jillion times. Where you been?
你是名人! 我多次找你，到哪了
- At a hotel. - Dad saw you at the golf course.
- 我到了酒店住 - 我爸f在球隹吹侥
- You sleepwalking again, buddy? - I don't want to talk about it.
- 又暨[了？ - 我不想
Now that you're famous, have a smoke.
你成了名，先抽支
What happens if you tell Mom and Dad, Sam?
若你告V爸l生什N事？
- You'll put Ariel in the garbage disposal. - Goddamn right, I will.
- 你G掉我的洋娃娃 - f得Γ我那幼
- So grody. - Hey, Cherita, you want a cigarette?
- 那N凶 - 雪，你要抽支幔
- Shut up! - "Shut up!"
- “周”! - “周”
Go back to China, bitch!
回中去吧，八婆
Just leave her alone.
放^她
- That's some good shit, huh? - It's a fucking cigarette.
- 那真是正 - 那只是支
# I wanted to be with you alone
我想和你
# And talk about the weather
一下天
# But traditions I can trace against the child in your face
我哪隳上的童真看到了根源
# Won't escape my attention
我一直在注意你
# You keep your distance with a system of touch
你始K不接近我
# And gentle persuasion
我用厝岚涯阏鞣
# With one foot in the past now just how long will it last
往事]忘 矍橹火能S持多久
# No, no, no, have you no ambition?
y道你不心？
# You keep your distance with a system of touch
你始K不接近我
# And gentle persuasion
我用厝岚涯阏鞣
# I'm lost in admiration, could I need you this much?
我迷僦你，如此需要你
# Oh, you're wasting my time
你在\⑽业r光
# You're just just just wasting time
浪Mrg
# Something happens and I'm head over heels
F在我神魂倒
# I never find out till I'm head over heels
我懵然不知
# Ah, don't take my heart, don't break my heart
不要我的心
# Don't, don't, don't throw it away
不要忽我的垡
# In my mind's eye
在我的心e
# One little boy, one little man
我是小孩
# Funny how
真是滑稽
# Time flies #
r光w逝
"There would be headlines in the papers.
“那是蠹^l”
"The grown-up gangs who ran the betting at the wrestling and the barrow-boys
“B摔跤L的成年黑汀
"would hear with respect of how 0ld Misery's house had been destroyed.
和M惑仔也尊敬他
"It was as though this plan had been with him all his life, pondered through the seasons,
老可z家被У慕^ 那仿似跟S了他一生
"now, in his 15th year, crystallised with the pain of puberty."
逐年思索，S著青春期成L之 痛就在十五q那年m埃落定
What is Graham Greene trying to communicate with this passage?
葛m葛林在@e想要表_什N？
Why did the children break into 0ld Misery's house?
孩子槭颤N要老可z的家？
- Joanie? - They wanted to rob him.
- 妮？ - 他想打劫他
If you had actually read the short story, which was a whopping 13 pages,
若你有看@只有13的短篇 令你MM整晚，你便知道
you'd know that the children find a great deal of money in the mattress, but burn it.
他在床|找到X，但s掉
Donnie Darko, perhaps with your recent brush with mass destruction,
丁尼或以你近日接|大型…
you can give us your opinion.
破牡慕，能o我意
They say it when they flood the house, when they tear it to shreds,
他在用水浸房子rf得
that destruction is a form of creation, so burning the money is ironic.
破氖橇硪环N模式的造
They just want to see what happens when they tear the world apart.
那他X是NS刺 他只想看破氖澜怎
They want to change things.
他想改世界
- May we help you? - Yeah, I just registered.
- 我能湍幔 - 我入W
- They put me in the wrong class. - You look like you belong here.
- 看砭e英文班了 - 你看砗芎线m@e
Um... Where do I sit?
我坐哪e？
Sit next to the boy you think is the cutest.
坐在你J樽秀的男孩旁
- (MUTTERING) - Quiet!
安o!
Let her choose.
她x
Joanie, get up.
妮，^
Well, the construction guys say it will take about a week to fix the roof.
那航空公司最好不要弄er石
- They still don't know? - Know what?
- 他仍未知道？ - 知道什N？
- Where it came from? - 0h, no. They can't tell us.
- 引擎哪难e
Something about a matching serial number that got burned.
fC件a{了
I had to sign a form saying I wouldn't talk to anyone about it.
我要一份文件 保C我守秘密
So we can't tell anyone what nobody knows?
我不能告V人]人知道的事？
Yeah. But you tell... What's your doctor's name?
Γ但你告V了… 你的t生叫什N名？
- Dr Thurman, Dad. - Yes. Tell Dr Thurman whatever you want.
- 傅t生，爸爸 - Γ你什N也可告V傅t生
- Dad. - What?
- 爸 - 什N？
What's that woman doing in the middle of the damn road?!
那老婆在路中g做什N？
No mail today. Maybe tomorrow.
今天]信，明天吧
(INDISTINCT)
所有生物都孤地死去
What did she say to you?
她跟你f了什N？
- I made a new friend. - Real or imaginary?
- 我交了新朋友 - 真是幻想的？
- Imaginary. - Would you like to talk about this friend?
- 幻想的 - 你想你@新交的朋友幔
- Frank.
- 法m
- What did he say? - He said to follow him.
- 他f了什N？ - 他叫我跟S他
- Follow him? Where? - Into the future.
- 跟S他？到哪？ - 去未
And then what happens?
之後怎N了？
And then he said... then he said that the world was coming to an end.
然後他f 他f世界快到末日了
Do you think the world is coming to an end?
你J槭澜缈斓侥┤樟耍
No.
不
That's stupid.
那真蠢
(WOMAN ON TV) For my entire life, I was a victim of my own fear.
我一生都是受我的恐炙害
(WOMAN) I was feeding fear with food.
我用食物B育我的恐
Fear.
恐
Finally, I looked in the mirror.
最後，我看R子
Not just in the mirror. I looked THROUGH the mirror.
不是看反影，而是看穿R子
In that image, I saw my ego reflection.
我看到我的自我
For two years, I thought it was normal for a 10-year-old to wet the bed...
赡恚我一位一十q孩子
Shh! Quiet!
安oc!
But the solution was there all the time.
但解Qk法其一直在面前
I'm not afraid any more!
我不再害怕!
All over America, people have come together to join hands.
在全美，很多人都大力支持
People who believe that human life is absolutely too important,
他相信人命是太重要 太F的
too valuable and too precious to be controlled by fear.
不能被恐植倏v
(FRANK) Pay close attention. You could miss something.
你注意c，不可e^
"...and the prince was led into a world of strange and beautiful magic."
王子被У狡婷钅Хǖ氖澜
Wow.
哇
"The Last Unicorn" by Samantha Darko.
“最後的角F”丁莎著
- Give it back! - "There was once a unicorn named Ariel..."
- 拿回 - 那坝蓄^角F叫阿里
- You wrinkled it. - It's not wrinkled, Sam.
- 你弄了 - ]有
It's 7.45. The bus should've been here 20 minutes ago.
F在是7c45分 公20分前就砹
Maybe Martha finally went nuts and hijacked it.
可能莎l了神然後劫C
There's this rule - at 7.45, we get to go home.
我7c45分要回家 @是t
There's no rule.
]有t
Cherita, you should... go home.
查e塔，你回家了
Yeah, if you're here when the bus comes, we'll get in trouble.
如果公淼r候你在 @e逗留那你就有麻┝
- Shut up! - "Shut up!"
- ]嘴
Hey, Porky Pig... I hope you get molested.
死肥i，你被}_
Hey! Hey! I can't believe this!
我不能相信，]可能
School's closed today because it's flooded.
我f因W校水浸 今天不用上W
- No way! - Yeah.
- ]可能! -
Holy shit! That's the best news ever!
老天!那是我^最好的消息!
My God, is this ever going to stop?
那r停止？
Eventually, yes. But right now, I got 12 classrooms full of water.
t早停的. 但F在有12g型房水浸
All coming from a busted water main.
水全有爆掉的水喉
- What else?
- 有什N？
Principal Cole, I'll show you what else.
我你看有什N
That's unbelievable. That's solid bronze, isn't it?
不能置信.那是青~，幔
- Yep. - How did this happen?
- - 那怎能l生的？
I heard a cat burglar trashed everything and the Mongrel got his head cut off.
有\在夜晚入家e 搞得周一塌糊T，把蒙格的^砍了
- Hah! - True!
- - 那怎能l生的？
Beth's mom said the boys' locker room flooded and they found faeces everywhere.
柏芙f男水浸了 四是S
- What are faeces? - Baby mice.
- 什NS？ - 小老鼠
Hey.
嘿
Has anyone ever told you that you're sexy?
有o人f^你很性感？
I like your boobs.
我喜g你的波波
Hey.
嘿
School's cancelled.
不用上W
Do you want to walk me home?
你想陪我回家幔
Sure.
好吧
- Don't look so freaked. - I'm not.
- e那N怕 - 我不怕
Check your backpack. Those guys steal shit.
但你z查背包 他弁|西
Fuck 'em!
操他
- So, why'd you move here? - My parents got a divorce.
- 你楹搬磉@e？ - 父母x了婚
My mom got a restraining order against my stepdad. He has emotional problems.
向^父l禁止令 他情w有}
I have those, too. What kind does he have?
我也有 你爸情w如何有}？
He stabbed my mom four times in the chest.
他刺了我胸口四刀
0h. Did he go to jail?
噢.他有]有坐牢？
No, he fled. They still can't find him.
不，他逃了，仍未找到
Mom and I had to change our names. I thought Gretchen Ross was pretty cool.
- 但我和要改名Q姓 - 我J榱_桂春很好
I was in jail once. I mean... I burned down this house.
我也坐^一次牢 我意思是我了g屋
It was abandoned, but I got held back in school and I can't drive till I'm 21.
m然是空置的 P我^m上W及21q前不得_
But I'm over all of that.
但我已改^了
I'm... painting and stuff.
我在
Writing. I want to be a writer. Maybe a painter. Maybe both...
作.想做家或作家 或佣甲
I'll write a book and draw the pictures.
我，再插D
Then maybe people will understand me. I don't know, change things.
到r人便明白我改世界
Donnie Darko - what the hell kind of name is that? It's like a superhero or something.
丁尼，你名字好怪 像卡通人物，超人的名字
What makes you think I'm not?
你以槲也皇幔
I should go. For physics, Montinoff is having me write this essay -
我要走了，要做物理的功n
the greatest invention ever to benefit mankind.
人最ゴ蟮陌l明
It's Monnitoff. But that's easy. Antiseptics.
一莫老L格
Like, the whole sanitation thing. Joseph Lister, 1895.
易事，消毒水l生的} 列士特，1895年
Before antiseptics, there was no sanitation, especially in medicine.
在l明消毒前，tW很不l生
You mean soap?
你是f肥皂？
Well, I'm really glad school was flooded today.
我很高dW校今天水浸
Why is that?
槭颤N？
We'd never have had this conversation.
因槲铱筛你f
You're weird.
你真怪
Sorry.
Σ黄
No, that was a compliment.
不，那是F你
Well, look, uh...
看
You want to go with me?
你想跟我走幔
- Where do you want to go? - No, I mean, like, "go" with me.
- 你想去哪e？ - 不是，跟我走，是做我女友
- You know, like "going together". - Sure.
- 我@e是@咏械模一起走 - 好
0K. Where are you going?
好，你去哪e？
I'm going home.
我回家
(MUTTERS) Stupid... "Where are you going?"
多蠢g!“你去哪e？”
I'd like to try something new.
我今次想c新|西
Have you ever been hypnotised?
你^接受催眠幔
No.
]有
When I clap twice, you will wake up. Do you understand?
我拍上率帜惚阈 明白幔
- Yes. - So, tell me about your week.
- 明白 - 告V我本星期l生的事
I met a girl.
我JR了一女孩
What is her name?
她叫什N名字？
Gretchen.
桂春
We're going together now.
我走在一起了
Do you still think about girls a lot?
你r常想著那女孩？
Yeah.
是的
- How are things going at school? - I think about girls a lot.
- W校怎恿耍 - 我r常想著女孩
I asked you about school, Donnie.
我你W校的事，尼
I think about fucking a lot during school.
我在W校r常想著性
- What else do you think about during school? - "Married With Children".
- 你在W校r常想著什N？ -
- You think about your family? - I just turn down the volume
- 我{低音量…
and think about fucking Christina Applegate.
幻想和女主角
I asked you about your family.
我你家人的事
No.
不
I don't think about fucking my family. That's gross.
我不想治业募胰耍真f心
I'd like to hear about your friend Frank.
我想你的朋友法m的事
(PRINCIPAL) Sam Bylan.
卞森
Cherita Chen.
特
Donald Darko.
丁尼
Hey, you fuck!
喂，你@混球!
Did you say I flooded the school?
你f是我水浸W校的幔
- I didn't say shit. - Yeah, well, they think I did it.
- 我什N也]f -e人不是@诱f，他以槭俏
If you're innocent, then you have nothing to worry about, right?
若你是清白的 你便]必要心
Fuck you! You know what I think?
去你的! 你知道我怎N想的幔
I think you did it.
我J槭悄阕龅
Beer and pussy - that's all I need.
啤酒和女人 我所需要的就是如此
- We gotta find ourselves a Smurfette. - Smurfette?
- 我要找精`女 - 精`女？
Mm-hm. Not some tight-ass Middlesex chick.
不是些串串的陀地妹
Like, this cute little blonde that'll get down with the guys like Smurfette does.
是跟男人梳乎的金索女
Smurfette doesn't fuck.
精`女不梳乎
That's bullshit. Why do you think Papa Smurf made her?
U!她跟同伴! 否t精`爸爸怎生她出!
Because the other Smurfs were getting too horny.
就是因槠渌{精` n悠砹!
- Not vanity. I heard he was a homosexual. - Then she fucks them while vanity watches.
- 不，s不，f他是同性 -那她炙rs在旁看
What about Papa Smurf? He must get some action?
那精`爸爸又怎樱 有份幔
What he does, he films the gang-bang. Later on, he beats off to the tape.
他拍z集w性鄞 然後看影а
First of all, Papa Smurf didn't create Smurfette. Gargamel did.
首先，精`不是精`爸爸做的
She was sent as Gargamel's evil spy to destroy the Smurf village,
加加R做的，她是他派淼募榧 榱缢{精`村
but the overwhelming goodness of the Smurfs transformed her.
但{精`的善良改了她
And as for the whole gang-bang scenario, it just couldn't happen!
而P於集w性鄞鸬} 根本不l生!
Smurfs are asexual. They don't even have reproductive organs under those little pants.
{精`是o性的，在他小小 白\子eB生殖器官也]有
That's what's so illogical about being a Smurf.
那就是{精`不合的地方
What's the point of living if you don't have a dick?
]有了何B仔生存有什N意思
Donnie, why you gotta get smart on us?
的尼，楹我那N醒？
- (H0RN H0NKS) - Grandma Death.
死亡婆婆
(MISS FARMER) Excuse me! Excuse me!
Σ黄!Σ黄!
Please stay off the road, Miss Sparrow, or I will call Social Services.
不要y^R路，史太太 若再l生，我便要找福利署了
I hate that Miss Farmer. She's such a fucking bitch!
我最憎那樊老 真是臭婆娘
Yeah.
是的
- How old is Grandma Death? - (D0NNIE) 101.
- 婆婆多老了？ - 101q
She does the same thing every day.
她每天也做同一拥氖
Just walks back and forth and back and forth to the mailbox.
在]箱前行硇腥
Nothing ever in there.
]有信
0h, wait, wait, wait...
等一下，等一下…
She's going back to the box. We may still have mail.
- 她走了，又去]箱 - 今天可能收到信了
- Mail, mail, mail. - Here it is.
- 信，信，信… - 有了
This could be it. 0h?
@可能就是了
- 0h, no dice, Grandma. Sorry. - Someone ought to write that bitch.
- 真]\猓下次吧! - 找人信o她
(TV) Authorities continued their search
警方今日仍在{查…
for a suspect in the Middlesex Ridge School vandalism.
山脊中W的破rg
The private school has asked for donations to restore its beloved mascot,
@g私校要求捐I…
known only as the Mongrel...
S修W校吉祥物的“大狗”
It's very helpful. There's a good turnout tonight.
o急家L教h 今晚7c正
What are you trying to accomplish here?
我B同郡警方
There was urine and faeces flooded in my office.
我的k公室e屎尿M流
Whatever fits.
f事皆
"Whatever fits"?
f事皆？
In cooperation with the county police,
我B同郡警方
we have begun an active investigation into the cause of the flooding.
已_始{查水浸事件
And our suspects include several of our own students...
疑犯包括我酌W生
I want to know why this filth is being taught to our children.
我想知道楹教孩子@些垃圾
Kitty, I would appreciate if you would wait...
我也想知道，蒂，f吧! 若能等…
Dr Cole, not only am I a teacher, but I am also a parent of a Middlesex child.
高博士，我不止是教 也是@eW生的家L
Therefore I am the only person here who transcends the parent-teacher bridge.
所以我是在@e唯一 能代表教家Lf的人
(FRANK) Don't worry. You got away with it.
e心，你逃的
I have in my hand Graham Greene's "The Destructors".
我手上是葛m葛林的
This short story is part of my daughter's English assignment.
@短篇故事是我女旱墓φn
In this story, several children destroy an elderly man's house from inside out.
在故事e，孩子 完全破牧艘老房子
How can you do that?
你怎能做得到
And how do they do this? They flood the house by breaking through a water main.
他怎做到呢？ 就是破牧丝喉，水浸房子
I can do anything I want.
我什N也能做到
And so can you.
你也是
And I think that this garbage should be removed!
我J轫消p@拥睦圾
Excuse me. What is the real issue here? The PTA doesn't ban books.
Σ黄穑主要的}是什N？ 家L教不禁的
The PTA must acknowledge that pornography is being taught in our curriculum!
家L教是要承J n程教授不雅物品!
- It's meant to be ironic. - Excuse me. Go back to grad school.
-那故事是S刺的 -Σ黄穑你回去W堂吧
Why did you make me flood the school?
你槭颤N迫我水浸W校？
They are in great danger.
他有危U
Do you even know who Graham Greene is?
你知否葛林是l？
I think we have all seen "Bonanza".
我想我都看^他的目
Well, um... while we are on other topics...
那，我在e的}r
Where do you come from?
你哪恚
Do you believe in time travel?
你相信r光旅行幔
(SAMANTHA) Who are you talking to?
你在跟lf？
I was just taking my pills, Sam.
我只是在吃，莎
A storm is coming, Frank says.
法m克f一霰╋L雨要砹
A storm that will swallow the children,
暴L雨⑼淌珊⒆拥纳命
And I will deliver them from the kingdom of pain.
我解除他的痛苦
I'll deliver them back to their doorsteps, send the monsters back to the underground.
我要送他回家 把病魔sM地z
I'll send them back to a place where no one else can see them.
把他送到一只有我
Except for me.
才能看他的地方
Because I am Donnie Darko.
因槲沂钱尼
Who is Frank?
法m克是娜位？
- A six-foot-tall bunny rabbit. - (GIGGLING)
一六尺高的兔子
In these modern times, our attitude and beliefs are so delicate, so fragile.
我的B度和信念都如此的易碎
I have had a Cunning Vision. This vision has released me.
我有N超常X 它把我闹嗅放了
It's important that our lifeline be rejuvenated, so that we can breathe again.
我又重@青春，重新呼吸
It's time to breathe.
是r候呼吸了
Thank you, Jim Cunningham.
xx你，郭占
So now let us begin Lifeline Exercise Number One. Please press stop now.
我_始 生命@日按停
As you can see, the lifeline is divided into two polar extremes.
你可以看生命是分成O的
Fear and love.
恐趾
Fear is in the negative energy spectrum.
恐治混敦O力量
- Love is in the positive energy spectrum. - No, duh (!)
- 畚混墩O力量 - 不
Excuse me? "No, duh" is a product of fear.
Σ黄穑 “不啦”是恐值慕Y果
Now, on each card is a character dilemma which applies to the lifeline.
F在每一卡些都有一 人生y}P乎生命的
Please... Take this. Thank you.
拿@xx
Please read each character dilemma aloud
x出每l人生y}
and place an "X" on the lifeline in the appropriate place.
在生命^的地方打交叉
Cherita?
雪？
"Juanita has an important math test today.
妮今日有重要的底y
"She's known about the test for several weeks, but has not studied.
她早前已知有y，但]亓
"In order to keep from failing, Juanita decides to cheat on the math test."
榱瞬幌氩缓细袼Q定作弊
Good. Good. Very good.
好，好，很好
Mr Darko.
丁先生
"Ling Ling finds a wallet filled with money.
玲玲找到有很多X的X包
"She takes it to the address on the driver's licence but keeps the money."
也㈠X包送回了地址 但收起了X
I'm sorry, Miss Farmer. I don't get this.
Σ黄穑攀老，我不明白
Just place an "X" in the appropriate place.
在^的地方打交叉便可
I know what to do, but you can't lump things into two categories.
“我只怎做，但我只是不明白， 凡事不只有擅妫K非那N巍
The lifeline is divided that way.
生命是那臃值
Well, life isn't that simple. I mean...
生命K非如此
Who cares if Ling Ling keeps the money? It has nothing to do with fear or love.
l理玲玲退X包但保留X？ 那跟酆涂秩]PS
- They are the deepest human emotions. - 0K. But you're not listening to me.
- 恐趾凼侨诵宰钌畹那榫w - 好，但你]有到我的
There are other things to take into account, the whole spectrum of human emotion.
有其它需要考]的地方 像人其它的情w
You can't just lump everything into two categories and deny everything else!
你不能只分成深 不其它!
If you don't complete the assignment, you'll get a zero.
若你不完成功n 今日得零分
Donald, let me preface this by saying
尼，在_始之前我想先f
that your lowa Test scores are... intimidating.
你在艾俄A州y的成令人@
So...
那
Let's go over this again. What exactly did you say to Miss Farmer?
再戆 你跟攀老f了什N
I'll tell you. He asked me to forcibly insert the lifeline exercise card into my anus!
我告V你他f了什N 他叫我塞生命卡入肛T!
Nobody cares about responsibility, morality, family values...
o人P心任，道德，家庭^念
Kitty... Excuse us, please.
Σ黄
They've suspended him from after-school activities for six months.
他禁止他⒓酉掳肽暾n外活
Since this jet engine fiasco, I don't know what's gotten into...
在引擎事件後，我不知他怎N了
I'll say this because our daughters are on the dance team together and I respect you,
我δ阏f是我女赡 一同跳舞，而也因大家是女性
but after witnessing your son's behaviour, I have significant doubts about your...
但C你鹤拥男獒 我最重岩赡愕摹
0ur paths through life must be righteous. Go home and look in the mirror
我人生道路必正 我衲慊丶蚁肭宄
and pray that your son doesn't succumb to the path of fear.
祈求你翰 `工M入恐值牡缆
Do you remember that weird gym teacher, Mrs Farmer?
你得那奇怪的攀老幔
Yeah. 0K, well, my brother told her to shove a book up her ass today.
我哥叫她塞一本入屁股
And then my parents just bought him all this new shit.
我爸便o他I了很多的新|西
Yeah, I know. I wish a jet engine would fall on my room.
我知 我也希望wC收擎跌下
- Dr Monnitoff. - Donnie.
- 莫老 - 尼
Um...
嗯
I know this is gonna sound kind of weird, but do you know anything about... time travel?
我知有c奇怪 但你r光旅行有多少JR？
(M0NNIT0FF) A wormhole with an Einstein-Rosen bridge,
一由垡蛩固蚝B起的x洞
which is theoretically a wormhole in space controlled by man.
理上就是由人控制的x洞
So, according to Hawking, a wormhole may be able to provide a short cut
根霍金的理x洞能做成捷
for jumping between two distant regions of space-time.
B接^域的r空
So to travel back in time, you have to have a spaceship faster than the speed of light.
所以，若要r光倒流你需要 一架比光速更快的太空船
- Theoretically. - And be able to find a wormhole.
- 理是如此 - 要找x洞
The basic principles of time travel are there.
那些就是r光旅[的基本l件
Your vessel and portal. Your vessel can be anything.
w船和航道 w船可以是太空船
- Like a DeLorean? - Metal craft of any kind.
- 像“狄_太空漫旅” - 又或者任何金亠w行工具
You know, I love that movie. It's so... like, futuristic, you know?
我很喜g那影 拍得很富有砀校你明白幔
Listen, um... don't tell anybody that I gave you this.
著e告V任何人 我o了你@
Woman who wrote this used to teach here. She was a nun long before that.
作者以前在@e 教她本是修女
Then overnight she became this entirely different person.
一夜之g她了另一人
She up and left the church, wrote this book...
x_了教，了@
She started teaching science, right here at Middlesex.
她在@e教科W
Roberta Sparrow?
史露拔？
That's right.
]e
Roberta Sparrow.
史露拔
Grandma Death.
死亡婆婆
It's called "The Philosophy 0f Time Travel".
叫做
- What does philosophy have to do with it? - Guess who wrote it.
跟哲W有什NPS？ 我看，你猜是l的？
Who?
l？
Roberta Sparrow. Huh! She wrote a book.
史露拔哦，她了一本
- Grandma Death wrote a book. - That's a terrible nickname.
- 死亡婆婆了一本 - 那是可怕地的花名
We almost ran her down the other day.
那天差c撞倒她
She lives in that piece of crap house, and you know she's loaded.
她在那屋住但很有X
- You're right. - She was known for her gem collection.
- ]fe - 她以前因槭詹刂Y名
Kids used to go up there all the time and try to steal stuff from her.
孩子常到她家想偷|西
She became a total recluse.
她得很避世
Huh! I didn't know she was alive till we damn near knocked her down.
如非U些撞倒她 不知她仍在生
(DONNIE) She was just standing in the road, frozen.
她只是呆立在路中
I walked over to see if she was OK.
我走出看她有]有事
And she whispered in my ear.
她低^跟我f了拙湓
- What did she say? - I think Frank wants me to talk to her.
- 她f了什N？ - 法m想我跟她
He asked if I knew about time travel.
因樯洗嗡提起r光旅行的事
She wrote a book about it, so that can't be a coincidence, right?
而她了一本 那必不是巧合
What did she say to you?
史露拔跟你f了什N？
She said that every living creature on earth dies alone.
她f世上所有生物都孤死去
How did that make you feel?
那令你有什N感X？
It reminded me of my dog Callie.
令我想起我的狗哥利
She died when I was eight and she crawled underneath the... the porch.
它在我八qr死去 它爬到花@底
To die.
自死去
To be alone.
为去死
Do you feel alone right now?
你F在X得孤幔
I don't know...
我不知道
I'd like to believe I'm not, but I just...
我希望我不是，但
I've just never seen any proof, so I just don't debate it any more.
我]看^C 所以我不再q@事了
I could spend my whole life debating it over and over and still wouldn't have proof,
我可以一生不停q反 思量利弊，但仍]有C
so I just don't debate it any more.
所以我不再想了
It's absurd.
那真荒
The search for God is absurd?
找ど袷腔闹的事幔
It is if everyone dies alone.
若所有的人都孤去死去 那便是
Does that scare you?
你害怕幔
I don't want to be alone.
我不想孤
And his tapes have made me realise
他的影ё我明白
that for the last 39 years, I have been a prisoner of my own fear.
在^去39年 我是活在恐鹊那舴
Fear.
恐
You have got to meet this Jim Cunningham.
你要郭占了
I can't believe he's single.
我不能相信他仍是紊
(COMMENTATOR) It has been a disappointing night for these Super Bowl champions.
今晚是超碗冠 失望的一晚
(2ND COMMENTATOR) You're right, Dan. Coach Joe Gibbs is on the sidelines.
你f得Γ丹教在鲞 眼R滴水落石出
He's gotta be thinking, "What happened? What went wrong tonight?"
他定在想今晚l生了什N事
- (DAN) And here's the kick. - 0h!
@是_球
It's no good...
不好
- Shit, we need a quarterback. - We need a miracle.
- 我需要四分g和奇E - 我在安全球
- We need to go for a safety. - What the future holds for this MVP,
- 各人肯定R克的期望很大 - 那是肯定的
we'll have to wait and see.
@最有r值球T前途得拭目以待
You guys want anything?
你想要些什N幔
(TV) This week on "Who's The Boss?" Samantha borrows Tony's van
我去拿些啤酒
and gets caught without a licence.
然後因]有{陶斩被抓
(DAN) Better make sure we don't miss that one.
我Я陶瞻
Here we are again. Fourth down now...
我第四次去了
- (BELL RINGS) - (TEACHER) Tomorrow, we meet our partners
明天要_家L
for the Young Inventors' Fair.
介B他看“小小l明家展[”
What if you could go back in time and take those hours of pain
若你能回到那埃抹走痛苦
and replace them with something better?
Q上更好的|西，你如何
- Like images? - Yeah, a Hawaiian sunset
- 如映射幔 - 像夏威夷
or the Grand Canyon.
或大{谷
- Things that remind you how beautiful... - We've been going together for two weeks.
- 人感X世界美好的|西 - 我一起已有星期了？
Yeah?
是幔
Well, I er... I...
我
You want to kiss me?
你想吻我？
- I'm sorry, I... - Look, Donnie, wait. I just...
- Σ黄穑我 - 尼，等等，我只
- Well, I like you a lot. - I just want it to be at a time when... it...
- 我很喜g你 - 我只想在m的rg
- When what? - When it reminds me just...
- 什N？ - 我想到…
When it reminds you how beautiful the world can be?
你想到世界有多美妙 是幔
And there's some fat guy staring at us.
而Fs有班死肥仔在瞪著我
I don't think telling any woman to forcibly insert an object up her anus
我Jσ女士f要把 硬物硬插入她的肛T
is something that should go without consequence.
是件很乐氐氖虑
I think we should buy him a moped.
我找d的人o他做伴吧
I think we should get a divorce.
我x婚吧
- You won't tell Mom, will you? - Why would I?
- 你不告V吧 - 不
- You tell Mom everything. - No, I don't.
- 你都告V了 - ]
- Let me see it. - No, it's not finished. It's...
- 我看看 - 不行，]做完呢
0K. It's cool.
行了，e理了
That's scary.
真是可怕
You think?
你@N想？
Thank you for seeing us at such late notice.
xx你的接
- We both felt we should come and discuss... - What I think is going on with your son.
- 我X得是rg一起 - 我δ鹤拥挠^察
Yes.
是
Um... Well, he's er...
你知他的^去
You know about his past, and he was suspended from school
有他因侮辱老
for insulting his gym teacher.
被P停W
I'm not sure that's a good example. I think he had just cause.
那不是好例子 他有原因侮辱她
Rose, let me lay out what I believe is happening here.
露z，我ff我X得有何}
Donnie's aggressive behaviour... his increased detachment from reality,
呢的攻粜员憩F 他逐u抽xF
seem to stem from his inability to cope with the forces in the world
源於他o法接受他J槭
that he perceives to be threatening.
世上有恐哧性的事物
Has he ever told you about Frank?
他有o提起他的朋友法m？
Frank?
法m？
Yes, the giant bunny rabbit.
Γ那巨型兔子
The what?
什N？
I don't recall him ever having mentioned a rabbit.
我]印象他提起^一p兔子
Donnie is experiencing what is commonly called a daylight hallucination.
尼v^一N叫日g幻X的B
This is a common occurrence among paranoid schizophrenics.
是妄想精神分裂症 病人的病徵
- What can we do? - I would like to do more hypnotherapy...
- 我能怎做？ - 我想多c做催眠治
...and increase his medication.
和增加他的
Whatever will help him, really, is... That's why we're here.
只要能偷剿的… 所以我砹
We just would like him to experience some relief.
我只想他得到放
So if you think that more medication will do that,
若你J榧铀能偷剿
then I think we should give it a try.
那我一
It's complicated.
@犹}s了
Yeah?
是幔
There's like a force in your brain that just sends you someplace.
你Xe有N能量把你 У搅硗獾牡胤饺
Do you go someplace familiar?
你去到你熟悉的地方幔
No, but each time I keep waking up farther from my house.
每次醒砦叶及lF 在x家很h的地方
(GRETCHEN) Scary.
真人
Donnie Darko.
丁尼
I know.
我知道
- Good morning, you mongrels! - Good morning.
- 早晨好，你@班小狗! - 早晨好
Is that all you can muster? Good morning!
那就是最起诺牧 早晨好？
- Good morning! - Now, that's a tiny, tiny bit better.
- 早晨好! - 那好一cc了
But I still sense some students who are actually afraid to say "good morning".
但我仍能感受到有些W生害怕f“早晨好”
Good morning!
早上好
Yeah, that's what I like to hear! Too many young men and women today
Γ那就是我想到的! F在太多年p男女
are completely paralysed by their fears.
完成被他的恐种配了
They surrender their bodies to the temptation and destruction
他向毒品，酒精，婚前性行
of drugs, alcohol and premarital sex.
的T惑和p投降
Now, I'm going to tell you a little story today.
我F在要向你f故事
It's a heartbreakingly sad story about a young man
是令人心碎的悲K故事，主角的生命
whose life was completely destroyed by these instruments of fear,
被恐制
a young man searching for love in all the wrong places.
一在e`的地方 找鄣纳倌
His name was Frank.
他的名字叫法m
- We're moving through time. - What?
- 我在r光旅行 - 什N？
Hi. My stepsister, like, I sometimes worry that she eats too much.
我的^妹 我有r心她吃太多
- Shut up, Kim! - I'm just trying to help.
收，阿金!
0h, sweetheart, please! There's no reason to be embarrassed here.
甜心，e@!
Many times we eat because we are afraid to face our ego reflection.
我吃|西是因槲害怕面ψ约
We find ourselves looking at the mirror, rather than into and through the mirror.
看著R子s不敢深入地看下自己
When we do that, we can finally see how beautiful we are.
如果我@幼瞿俏就 lF我原硎沁@N美
- Thanks! - Sure. Come up here. Don't be afraid.
- xx - 磉@啊，e怕
Er, how can I find out what I wanna be when I grow up?
我怎能Q定我L大r要做什N？
0h! That's a hard one. Well, look deep inside of yourself, deep within your heart,
那是y} 深入你的刃氖澜
and find what makes you feel love - pure, unconditional love - and go to that.
找出那Nol件的壑根源
In your studies, in your athletics, in your relationships, go towards love.
o你在W上，在做\ 在和人交往都要依靠
- Thank you. - Come on up.
-xx - 鼓起
Next.
下一
- How do I learn how to fight? - "How do I learn how to fight?"
- 我怎涌梢W好打架？
Son, violence is a product of fear. Learn to truly love yourself -
暴力是恐值母碑a品 W去勰阕约
TRULY love yourself - and the world will be yours.
- 勰阕约 - @是你的世界
- 0K. - Get yourself up here!
- 好的 - 上!
All right!
好
- Good morning. - Good morning!
- 早晨
Um... How much are they paying you to be here?
他付多少X你恚
Er... Excuse me?
什N？
- What's your name, son? - Gerald.
- 你叫什N名字？ - x勒
Well, Gerald, I think you're afraid.
x勒，我J槟愫ε
Do you want us to buy your book? Because that was the worst advice ever.
你是否榱讼胛I你的？ 是的，是我到最差的窀
See how sad this is? Want your sister to lose weight?
- 看@多N可悲 - 你想你妹p肥？
Tell her to stop eating Twinkies and play field hockey.
叫她少吃甜食和出去玩曲棍球
No one knows what they want to be. It takes time to find that out. Right, Jim?
o人知道L大後想做什N 要慢慢l掘的
And you...
有你
Yeah, you.
Γ你
Sick of some jerk shoving your head down the toilet? Well, lift some weights
你了被人塞你的^入所？ 那你We重
or take a karate lesson, and next time kick him in the balls.
或W柔道，下次再有人 欺你便踢他要害
Son... See this? This is an anger prisoner, a textbook example.
孩子，看到幔 典型被怒操v的例子
- Prisoner. - Do you see the fear, people?
看到他的恐幔 他害怕真相
This boy is scared to death. Son, it breaks my heart to say this,
孩子，@诱f真我心
but I believe you're a very troubled and confused young man.
但我X得你是困惑的少年
- You are searching in all the wrong places. - You're right, actually.
- 我X得你在e`的地方找答案 - 你f得
I am pretty troubled and pretty confused.
我很困惑
And I'm afraid, really, really afraid. Really afraid, but I... I...
而我也怕，非常非常怕
I think you're the fucking Antichrist.
我怕你是魔鬼化身
It's amazing. He thinks he's telling the truth. Everything he says is a fucking lie.
真奇怪，那人以樽约赫f真 但其他f的一切都是大
Everything he says!
他f的一切!
Everyone thinks he's so rad. He's such a fucking chud...
人人以樗很正x. 但其一U人
Are you 0K?
你好幔
Sit down. Calm down.
坐下，冷o
You ever hear of Grandma Death?
你^死亡祖母幔
Who?
l？
"The Philosophy 0f Time Travel". What is this?
，是什N？
She wrote it.
是她的
I'm... I'm seeing stuff...
我看|西
Like really messed-up stuff.
很多不知名的|西
That book describes stuff I've been seeing, and it can't just be a coincidence.
@描述了我所到的一切 不只是巧合吧
She must be in. She never leaves this house.
她一定在，她牟浑x_家的
Maybe she's asleep.
可能她睡著了
Donnie, look.
尼，看
(FRANK) Send her a letter.
o封信她
(MONNITOFF) Each vessel travels along a vector through space-time,
每艘\工具都要在道上行走
along its centre of gravity.
穿梭r空，沿著中心
Like a spear.
像一支茅
- Pardon? - Like a spear coming out of your chest.
- Σ黄穑 - 像支由心口l出的茅
In order for the vessel to travel through time, it's got to find a portal, a wormhole or...
榱俗工具w越r空 我要找l通道，x洞或
Could these portals? Could these portals just appear anywhere, any time?
@些通道…？@些通道 能否在何r何地出F？
I think that's highly unlikely.
那不大可能
- No, you're talking about an act of God. - If God controls time, time is pre-decided.
- 你f的只有上帝能做到 - 若上帝控制rg，一切已]定
- I'm not following you. - Every living thing follows a set path.
- 我不明白 - 所有的生物S著已O定的路
And if you could see your path, then you could see the future?
若你到你的路 便能看到未
- That's a form of time travel. - Well, you're contradicting yourself.
- 那是r空穿梭的一N - 你自相矛盾
If we were able to see our destinies manifest themselves visually,
若我能看到自己的未
then we would be given a choice to betray our destinies.
那我便可以x窀淖未
The mere fact that this choice exists would make all preformed destiny come to an end.
@x癖旧矶已 令]定命\之f不能成立
Not if you travel within God's channel.
但若在上帝的工具中穿梭便不
I'm not going to be able to continue this conversation.
我不能^m@υ
- Why? - I could lose my job.
- 槭颤N？ - 我被炒
0K.
好的
It gives me no pleasure to deny you one of the great writers of the 20th century.
很z憾你K不是20世o 最ゴ蟮淖骷抑一
Alas, I have not yet been elected queen of the universe, so I must obey the rules.
我不是宇宙的女皇呢 要遵守t
So, anyone seen in this school reading this book will be suspended.
所以任何人在W校 看@本的都要停W
Not to worry. Someone pre-ordered a dozen copies at the Sarasota Mall bookstore.
e心，有人已在 _拉s塔店了凳本
In Mr Greene's absence, we will now be reading another classic - "Watership Down".
由於格林先生不在 我x另一本名著“水船”
Here, Donnie.
尼，
Pass these back.
把@些fo後面
Maybe you and Frank can read this one together.
你和法m克一起看@本 吧
(FRANK) Now you know where he lives.
F在你知道他住在哪e了
And they grow out of our... chest, solar plexus?
神光奈的胸口L出
Just like she described, the way they moved and they smelled.
像她中描述一拥B和馕
It's like they're workers.
它像工人
Assigned to each one of us. They just... They're like liquid.
每人都有，像是液晶
I followed it into my parents' bedroom.
我跟S它到我父母的房g
What did you find?
你找到什N？
Nothing.
什N也]有
So we call them IMGs.
我叫它IMG
- Infant Memory Generators. - You buy these glasses for your infant,
- 即ru造器 - 你I@些眼Ro你的
and they wear them at night when they sleep.
他在晚上睡Xr戴著
But inside the glasses are these slide photographs.
在眼睛扔邢嗥
Each photograph is of something peaceful or beautiful, whatever the parents want.
M是美和安o的食物 父母可以自行x
What effect would it have on an infant?
河惺颤N看法？
Well, nobody remembers their infancy. Anybody who says they do is lying.
那，o人得r f得是fe
So, this will help develop memory earlier in life.
我J檫@兔Πl展
Yeah.
是的
Did you consider that infants need darkness as part of their natural development?
有]有想^盒枰黑暗？ 黑暗是自然成L的一部分？
No.
不
What if the parents put in pictures of Satan or dead people?
若父母放撒旦 或死人的相M去呢？
Is that what you'd show your kids?
你o你的孩子看那些|西幔
Er, well, I mean, didn't your dad, like, stab your mom?
你爸不是拿刀插你幔
Get out.
出去
Gretchen!
桂春!
Gretchen! Gretchen. I'm sorry about those guys.
桂春!很Σ黄穑很抱歉那些人
- Two for "Evil Dead", please. - That'll be $2.
- - 盛惠二元
Why do you wear that stupid bunny suit?
你楹未┠前装V的兔子b？
Why are you wearing that stupid man suit?
你楹未┠前装V的人模b？
Take it off.
下
What happened to your eye?
你眼睛怎N了？
Why do they call you Frank?
你怎N叫法m？
It is the name of my father.
是我爸的名字
And his father before me.
有他爸的名字
Frank...
法m…
when's this going to stop?
@事r完？
You should already know that.
我X得你已知道
Watch the movie screen.
我想你看y幕
There's something I want to show you.
有些想你看的|西
Have you ever seen a portal?
你^通道幔
Burn it to the ground.
一把火它
0K. Now, girls, I want you to concentrate.
好了，女孩，我要你Ｐ
Failure is not an option.
失∈遣荒芙邮艿
And, Bethany, if you feel the need to vomit up there, just swallow it.
柏菲，若你在_上想I 便吞下肚
- 0K, Mom. - Hey, you guys, good luck out there.
- 好的， - 祝你好\
Now, that was really something.
那真是精彩的演出
Thank you, Cherita Chen, with "Autumn Angel".
xx雪演唱
Now the moment we've all been waiting for.
我期待已久的一刻K於砼R
It is my pleasure to introduce to you Emily Bates, Suzy Bailey,
很s幸能槟介B白勖溃柏Kz
Samantha Darko, Beth Farmer and Joanie James.
丁莎，樊柏菲，妮
They are Sparkle Motion.
她是“Wq感印
# No-No-Notorious
摹名
# I can't read about it
我x不懂
# Burns the skin from your eyes
你的火辣眼睛C了我的皮w
# I'll do fine without it
]有你我能活下去
# Here's one you don't compromise
你不肯妥f
# Lies come hard to disguise
e言y以遮w
# Let me to fight it out
我取
# Not wild about it
e生
# Lay your seedy judgements
碜Q定
# Who says they're part of our lives?
Q定是我生活的一部分
# You own the money, you control the witness
你有X，你控制著目糇C人
# I hear you're lonely, don't monkey with my business
你寂寞，e搞我
# You pay the profits to justify the reasons
你耍手段慝@利
# I heard your promise, but I don't believe it
我不信你的Z言
# That's why I've done it again
我又@幼
# No-No-Notorious... #
拿
How long was I asleep for?
我睡了多久？
Whole movie.
整部虻rg
Well, look what the cat dragged in!
看看那只砹耸颤N|西
How you doing, Donnie?
尼，怎N了
Your little sister was broken-hearted that you missed her big show last night.
昨晚你]看你妹妹的精彩表演 真是透了她的心
- Dad? - Hm?
- 爸爸？ - 嗯？
I'm crazy.
我了
You're not crazy.
不是
I used to be crazy.
我曾狂^
But you're not crazy.
不^你不是
- Look, you're my only son... - I know...
- 你是我H有的鹤 - 我知道
No, hold it. I know I'm not the best communicator, but...
拿著，我知道我不善於贤
...whatever happens to you, be honest, tell the truth,
但如果你有什N事 老告V我
even if they do look at you funny - they will.
就算是他δK不友好
But what you gotta understand, son,
不^你要明白
is that almost all of those people are full of shit.
@些人都不是好|西
They're all part of this great big conspiracy of bullshit.
他思K⑴c了@\
And they're scared of people like you.
他害怕像你@拥娜
Because those bullshitters know that you're smarter than all of them.
因檫@筒俚暗砘 知道你比他明
You know what you say to people like that? Hm?
@拥娜f什N呢？
"Fuck you."
“操你娘”
The blaze was extinguished sometime after 8.00 last night.
火在晚上8r被
Firefighters discovered what has been referred to as a kiddie porn dungeon.
消防TlF了一gΥ媪 大量和色情D缘牡乩
Cunningham, who has become a recent celebrity for his books, was arrested...
近日因自助D成名的郭占 今晨在l村俱凡俊
- 0h, my God! ...while at Sarasota Heights Country Club.
- 老天! - 被拘捕
Arson has not been ruled out as the cause of the fire.
未排除起火原因是v火
- Now a group of Cunning Vision employees... - Dad played golf with that guy.
- F在一班郭氏的T… - 爸常跟那人一起打高夫球
...vehemently denied the alleged link to a child pornography publishing circuit.
烈否Jc出版和春mD集有P
In a vicious statement, Connie attacked fire department officials,
郭占在明中乐刂肛消防署
claiming a mass conspiracy.
指事情是插\{的\
I'm sorry, Karen. This is a progressive school,
Σ黄穑嘉 @是M步的W校
but we don't feel your methods are appropriate.
但我J槟阌玫姆椒ú贿m
What exactly about my methods are inappropriate?
]有不敬 但你f怎才叫m？
I am sorry that you have failed.
Σ黄穑但你失×
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have another appointment.
Σ黄穑我另有事k
You can finish out the week.
你可留到星期五
Fuck!
的!
Good afternoon. It's a great pleasure to announce
午安!我很高d能告V大家山脊中W…
that the Middlesex Ridge School dance team
被x中到加州洛杉…
has been invited to perform on "Star Search '88" in Los Angeles.
上目
- I know now a terrible thing is coming. - What do you mean?
- 我A感到有氖乱l生了 - 什N意思？
The field, the field. It's covered with blood.
田野上都是血
Blood? Don't be silly.
血？ef傻了
All right. It's getting dark. We should get back to the burrow.
好了，天黑了，要回洞了
Back to the burrow? It'll come there. It's all around us!
洞？它就在我周
- Stop it, Fiver. - We've got to leave here.
- M瓦，ef了 - 我要x_@
When the other rabbits hear of Fiver's vision, do they believe him?
e的兔子到M瓦P於他 的幻X的，他相信他幔
Why should we care?
我才不P心呢
Because the rabbits are us, Donnie.
因槲是兔子，尼
Why should I mourn for a rabbit?
槭颤N我要橐浑b兔子y^？
Is the death of one species less tragic than another?
一物N的缤比 另一物N的消失更悲K
0f course. A rabbit's not like us.
兔子和我不同
It has no history books, no photographs, no knowledge of sorrow or regret.
我]有v史，照片 不懂得悲和後悔
I'm sorry. Don't get me wrong, I like rabbits. They're cute and horny.
Σ黄穑e`我，我喜g兔子 他又可塾诸B皮
If you're cute and horny, you're happy. You don't know why you're alive.
如果你又可塾诸B皮，你快 你不知道你槭颤N要活著
You just want to have sex as many times as possible before you die.
你只想在死前能M情享受性
I just don't see the point in crying over a dead rabbit...
σ活^死去的兔子 流眼I毫o意x
who never even feared death to begin with.
因槟峭米佣疾慌滤
You're wrong. These rabbits are the product of the author's imagination.
你e了，@些兔子是作者 想像出淼
He cares for them, so we care for them, otherwise we've just missed the point.
他很P心他 不然我的就]意x
Aren't we forgetting about the miracle of storytelling?
我忘了v故事的奇妙之幔
The deus ex machina? The god machine?
神之C器？
That's what saved the rabbits.
@救了兔子一命
No, it was ridiculous. I'll call you back.
不，那多荒 我回^o你
- Rose. - Kitty.
- 露z - 蒂
I'm sure you've heard the horrible allegations against Jim Cunningham.
我知道你定知道郭占的可怕起V
I know. Something about a kiddie porn dungeon...
我知道，f什N和春m地牢
0h, please, please! Don't use those words!
求你!e@诱f!
It's obviously a conspiracy to destroy an innocent man.
很明@是\
I'm spearheading the Jim Cunningham defence campaign.
我l起了qo郭占的行
Rose, I have to appear at his arraignment tomorrow morning.
露z，明早我要去他的提V
The girls have to leave for Los Angeles.
你也知道舞蹈今早要⒊痰铰迳即
As their coach, I was the obvious choice to chaperone them.
作榻叹我以Oo人身份同行
- But now you can't go. - Yes.
- 但你F在不能去 -
Now, believe me, of all the other mothers, I would never dream of asking you.
我本不想你
But none of the others are available.
但其他]一能走_
I don't know, Kitty. It's a bad weekend. Eddie's in New York.
我不知道，蒂. @L末不方便，艾迪去了~s
Rose, I don't know if you realise what an opportunity this is for our daughters!
我不知道你明不明白@是 我女憾嚯y得的C!
This has been a dream of Samantha's and all of ours for a long time.
@是莎和我女阂幌虻粝
I made her lead dancer!
我她做女主角!
Sometimes I doubt your commitment to Sparkle Motion!
有r我岩赡Wq痈械恼\意
Elizabeth will be in charge.
伊莉
She'll drive you to therapy.
d你到心理t生
And if you need anything, you promise me that you will call Dr Thurman?
答我有什N需要r 找Mt生
How does it feel to have a wacko for a son?
有怪鹤拥母杏X如何？
It feels wonderful.
非常美妙
Here... Sorry! Here you are!
Σ黄穑你在@e
- You guys are gonna win. I know it. - (SAM) So do I.
- 你要A了 - 我也是
Here's the keys. There's food in the fridge and do not...
匙在@e，冰箱有食物
Mom, go. You're gonna miss your plane.
快走，wC要起w了
Mom, I need...
，我要
There's nothing broken in my brain.
我的X子有cy
- I know. - Bye, Donnie.
- 我知道 - 尼，再
0K, go. Go!
走吧
Hello, Donnie.
你好，尼
It's Friday. Shouldn't you be off with your friends, scaring old people?
今天星期五 你不要和你那班朋友一起人了
- What's going on? - I don't know. That's a good question.
- 什N事？ - 我不清楚，你得好
I'm no longer your English teacher. They fired me.
我不是你的英Z老了 他解雇了我
That's bullshit! You're the only good teacher here.
真K! 你是@e唯一好的老
Thank you.
xx
What's "cellar door"?
什N是“地窖T”
This famous linguist once said that of all the phrases in the English language,
有著名的Z言W家曾f^
of all the endless combinations of words in all of history,
在英Z措o千fNM合中
"cellar door" is the most beautiful.
“地窖T”是最美的
"Cellar door."
“地窖T”
I promise that one day everything's gonna be better for you.
我保CK有一天一切改
Shut up!
收!
(DR THURMAN) I want to talk about your past. (DONNIE) No.
- 我今日想跟你你的^去 - 不
I want to talk about you and your parents.
你和你父母
(DONNIE) They didn't buy me what I wanted for Christmas.
他}Q]I我想要的|西o我
What did you want for Christmas that year?
你那年想要什N拥亩Y物？
Hungry Hungry Hippos.
I河R
How did you feel, being denied these Hungry Hungry Hippos?
你]有收到I河R有何感X？
- Regret. - What else makes you feel regret?
- 後悔 - 有什N令你後悔？
- That I did it again. - You did it again?
- 我又再犯了 - 你又犯了？
I flooded my school and I burned down that pervert's house.
我水浸了W校和那B佬的家
(LAUGHS) I only have a few days left before they catch me.
有滋焖那便碜轿
- Did Frank tell you to do these things? - I have to obey him. He saved my life.
- 是法m叫你@幼龅幔 - 我定要服乃，他救我一命
I have to obey him or I'll be left all alone.
我要服乃 否t他x我
And then... And then I won't be able to figure out what this is all about.
之後…之後我便不能知道 @些事情的意思
I won't know his master plan.
我不能知道他的
Do you mean God's master plan?
你指上帝的？
Do you now believe in God?
你F在信不信上帝？
I have the power to build a time machine.
我有能力造一架r光C
How is that possible?
怎能做到？
How is time travel possible, Donnie?
怎能穿梭r空？
Time's up, Frank said.
rg到了，法mf
- When is this going to happen? - Soon.
- @事何rl生？ - 快了
What is going to happen?
l生什N事？
- Frank is gonna kill. - Who is he going to kill?
- 法m大_⒔ - 他⒄l？
- I can see him!
- 我F在到他!
The sky's gonna open up.
天空打_
If the sky suddenly opened up, there would be no law, no rule.
若天空突然打_ 世界oo律
There would only be you and your memories,
只剩下你和你的
the choices you've made and the people you've touched.
你的x瘢你接|^的人
If this world were to end, there would only be you and him...
若@世界KY 只剩下你和他…
...and no one else.
]有其他人
You can stop taking your medication.
你不用服了
They're placebos. Just pills made out of water.
那是定 只是用水作出淼乃
Thank you.
xx
Donnie...
尼
An atheist is someone who denies altogether the existence of God.
所^o神者就是否J神之存在的人
You're an agnostic.
你是不可知者啊
An agnostic is someone...
不可知者就是
who believes that there is no proof of the existence of God,
J槭澜缟]有@示 神之存在的C的人
but does not deny a possibility that God exists.
但他不否J神存在的可能性
Goodbye, Dr Thurman.
再了，瑟曼先生
Hey.
嘿
I got in.
我入了
I'm going to Harvard.
我被哈佛大W取了
Hey, we should totally throw a party. Mom and Dad are gone.
我_派c祝 爸不在
- It's Halloween. We could get away with it. - 0K. But it has to be small.
- 又是f}，一起狂g - 好吧，但只能是小型派Γ好幔
We got eggs, water balloons and a dozen rolls of toilet paper.
我有蛋 充水的馇蚝鸵淮
I stole four beers from my dad.
我自我爸偷了四灌啤酒
- We got a keg. - Keg beer is for pussies.
- 我有整桶 - 女人才那N
Rose, this is Lilian Thurman.
露z，@是M莉仁
It is important that you call me as soon as you get this message. Thank you.
很重要的事 到快恢停xx
You 0K?
你]事吧？
Yeah. My mom's gone.
我走了
You want to come in?
想M幔
I don't know. She didn't leave a note and the house was all messed up.
我不知道，她]留下字l 整g物混y一片
But you're 0K.
但你]事
Did you call the cops?
你有]有缶？
Yeah, they said I should leave the house and that I should go to a safe place.
有，他f我快 x_到安全的的地方
I'm just so scared. I keep thinking something awful is happening and...
我很害怕 我知l生了可怕的事
It's my fucking stepdad, I know it.
我知一定是我那^父
I guess some people are just born with tragedy in their blood.
有些人天生是悲∪宋
- Hey, have you seen Frank? - No, they went on a beer run.
- 有]有看到法m？ - ]有，他去拿啤酒了
(ROSE) If you're there, please pick up. Oh, well. Good news.
若你在，.好消息
The girls got three and a half stars and are in the quarter-finals.
跳舞得到三粒半星 她要胡⒓影Q
Samantha was amazing. Anyway...
真美妙，之…
We're taking the red-eye back tonight and...
我今晚s夜C回
- Mom, we've got to leave. - Yeah. 0K.
- ，wC要起w了 - 好的
We should arrive 8:30 in the morning.
我今晚夜C回 明早8c半到
Um... I hope everything's... I hope everything's all right.
希望一切安好
I love you. Bye.
我勰，拜拜
# Fate
命\
# Up against your will
K不如你所
# Through the thick and thin
D苦重重
# He will wait until
他一直等
# You give yourself to him
直到你向他屈服
- Come with me. - Where are we going?
- 跟我 - 我去哪e？
- Donnie? - Look, we gotta go.
- 尼？ - 看，我要走了
- We've got to see Grandma Death. - Why? About the book?
- ^死亡祖母幔 - P於那些幔
- No, it's Frank. - Donnie...
- 不P於法m的事情 - 尼…
Time is running out! We gotta go.
]rg了!我要走了
Donnie, nobody's here. Let's just forget about it.
尼，]人在，是算了吧
"Cellar door."
“地窖T”
What?
什N？
Donnie! Donnie!
天老!尼!尼!
Donnie!
尼!
- Why the fuck are you here? - 0h, my God!
- 你槭颤N在@e？ - 上帝!
- You're dead! - What do we do?
- 你死定了! - 我怎N置？
- Shit! - Leave them alone!
- 的! - 放他走!
Don't fucking move! Don't fucking move!
e!的千fe!
- There's a car! - (C0UGHS)
那e有v!
- Get the hell out of here! - Come on!
- 立即出! - 出!
Seth, a car's coming. Let's go!
沙夫，有v正_^ 我走吧!
I have a bigger knife now.
我有把大刀了
Fuck!
的!
Did you call the fucking cops?
是你缶的幔
- Deus ex machina. - What did you just say?
- 我的救主 - 你f什N了？
- What the fuck did you say? - 0ur saviour.
- 你f什N？ - 我的救主
Donnie!
尼
Frank...
法m…
Is she dead?
她死了幔
What were you guys doing in the middle of the road?!
你在路中心稚叮 ]用X幔
Go home!
回家!
Go and tell your parents everything will be 0K.
回家告V你父母 一切]事!
Go!
去!
The storm is coming. You must hurry.
暴L雨要砹耍快c
I'm going home.
我要回家了
(DONNIE) Dear Roberta Sparrow, I've reached the end of your book
H鄣氖仿栋 我哪接|到你
and there's so many things I need to ask you.
我有很多}想你
Sometimes I'm afraid of what you might tell me.
有r我害怕你回答我
Sometimes I'm afraid that you'll tell me this is not a work of fiction.
f@不是的
I can only hope that the answers will come to me in my sleep.
我只希望我在糁姓业酱鸢
I hope that when the world ends,
我希望世界KYr…
I can breathe a sigh of relief because there will be so much to look forward to.
我得到放 因橐期待太多事了
# All around me are familiar faces
“周是我熟悉的面孔”
# Worn-out places, worn-out faces
“破f的世界，疲v的面孔”
# Bright and early for their daily races
“他的新生的孔透著光A”
- # Going nowhere, going nowhere - (S0BS)
“o可去”
# Their tears are filling up their glasses
“眼R沾MI水”
# No expression, no expression
“不要f”
# Hide my head, I want to drown my sorrow
“把^藏起恚我要忘掉悲”
# No tomorrow, no tomorrow
“]有明天”
# And I find it kinda funny
“我X得@很有趣”
# I find it kinda sad
“@很令人神”
# The dreams in which I'm dying are the best I've ever had
“我舻轿乙呀死去，真是美妙”
# I find it hard to tell you
“我y以X”
# I find it hard to take
“y以接受”
# When people run in circles
“人在兜圈”
# It's a very, very
“@是一如此”
# Mad world
“狂的世界”
# Children waiting for the day they feel good
“孩子在等待白天的Y束 他X得妙O了”
# Happy birthday, happy birthday
“生日快贰
# Made to feel the way that every child should
“每孩子都有@N感X”
# Sit and listen, sit and listen
“坐下砺我v”
# Went to school and I was very nervous
“到了W校就精神不安”
# No one knew me, no one knew me
“]有人t解我”
# Hello, teacher, tell me what's my lesson
“老，告知我的n程”
# Look right through me, look right through me
“氐浊宄我”
# And I find it kinda funny
“我X得@很有趣”
# I find it kinda sad
“@很令人神”
# The dreams in which I'm dying are the best I've ever had
“我舻轿乙呀死去，真是美妙”
# I find it hard to tell you
“我y以X”
# I find it hard to take
“y以接受”
# When people run in circles
“人在兜圈”
# It's a very, very
“@是一如此”
# Mad world
“狂的世界”
# Enlarging your world
“拓你的界”
Hey. What's going on?
嘿，l生什N事？
Horrible accident. My neighbour... got killed.
乐厥鹿.我的居…. 死了
- What happened? - Got smushed by a jet engine.
- 是怎N回事？ - wC引擎涸伊
What was his name?
他叫什N？
Donnie. Donnie Darko.
尼.丁尼
I feel bad for his family.
他家的事情真令人心
Yeah.
是的
Did you know him?
你JR他幔
No.
不JR
# Oh, say, can you see
“哦，f你能看到”
# By the dawn's early light
“黎明的晨曦吧”
# What so proudly we hailed
“在黎明的最後一|光亮中”
# At the twilight's last gleaming?
“我如此自豪地g呼什N？”
# Whose broad stripes and bright stars
“是l的明朗的ly和W耀的星星”
# Through the perilous fight
“穿越^我…”
# O'er the ramparts we watched
“守l的危U堡尽
# Were so gallantly streaming?
“是否如此勇敢的川流”
# And the rockets' red glare
“有火箭的t光…”
# The bombs bursting in air
“空中爆l的炸”
# Gave proof through the night
“C明在@暗夜中…”
# That our flag was still there
“我的旗萌粤⒅”
# O say, does that star-spangled banner yet wave
“f，那星光N的旗 仍h釉凇”
# O'er the land of the free
“自由的土地”
# And the home of the brave? #
“和勇敢的土上？”